# Roy Emmanuel S. Medina

#### **PROFILE**

Data Engineer with experience designing, planning, and executing the development of business software applications for automated data collection, analytical reporting, and driving decisions in a fast-paced medical device manufacturing environment. Skilled in developing data transformation pipelines to feed reporting dashboards and driving decisions for production managers and engineers.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Dexcom – Data Engineer I

(October 2021 – Present)

- Designed, engineered, and deployed an ETL script to enable Quality Compliance and Manufacturing Training teams with access to employee training data with the release of a new Learning Management System
- Designed and developed a web application to enable Process Sustaining Engineers with real-time access to track and trend product rejects collected throughout the manufacturing floor
- Develop lesson plans and led a series of workshops to over 50 employees covering the fundamentals of Python programming

#### Dexcom – Data Analyst

(February 2020 – August 2021)

- Developed a Python Flask Web App to collect manufacturing equipment downtime data to provide engineers with insights and trends on Overall Equipment Effectiveness metrics for capacity planning and continuous improvement projects for equipment
- Developed ETL scripts to extract, transform, and load datasets from various Microsoft SQL server sources onto the enterprise Google Cloud Platform for connectivity to live Tableau reporting

### University of San Diego – Student Hardware and Software Lead

(August 2019 – May 2020)

- Prepare and provide training on enterprise IT equipment troubleshooting and information workflow processes
- Develop and document standard procedures to identify and resolve hardware and software issues

#### University of San Diego - Student Technician

(August 2018 – August 2019)

 Hands-on troubleshoot, diagnosis, and repairs on computers and devices of campus's community members Analytics Engineer

#### **Data Engineer**

Industrial and Systems Engineer

#### **CONTACT**

- **1** (619)-212-1397
- ♠ San Diego, CA 92121

#### **SKILLS**

 $(\bullet = 1 \text{ year of experience})$ 

#### **Software Languages**

Python
SQL
R
HTML/CSS/JS

#### Software

MS Office Suite
Linux Terminal
Tableau
Power Apps

•••••

## EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES

#### **University of San Diego**

2017 - 2021

BS/BA, Industrial and Systems Engineering GPA: 3.52

#### Lean Six Sigma Green Belt

Issuer: University of San Diego

#### **Google Cloud Hero Core Infrastructure I**

Issuer: Google Cloud

#### Google Cloud Hero Core Infrastructure II

Issuer: Google Cloud